doctors.net.uk 2019-12-10

# Privacy policy and cookies notice

       Privacy policy and cookies notice
1.   Introduction
1.1. This privacy notice aims to inform you about how M3 (EU) Limited (referred to as “M3”, “we”,
     “us” or “our” in this privacy notice) processes your personal data and tells you about your
     privacy rights under data protection laws.
1.2. For the purposes of EU data protection laws, we are the ‘controller’ of the personal data we
     collect about you through and in connection our operation of the Doctors.net platform.
1.3. Doctors.net incorporates privacy controls for members which affect how we will process your
     personal data. By using the privacy controls, you can specify your marketing and
     communications preferences and limit the publication of your information. You can access
     the privacy controls via https://www.doctors.net.uk/updateyourprofile/default.aspx.
2.   How we use your personal data
2.1. In this Section 2 we have set out:
     •      the general categories of personal data that we process;
     •      in the case of personal data that we did not obtain directly from you, the source and
            specific categories of that data;
     •      the purposes for which we may process personal data; and
     •      the legal bases of the processing.
2.2. Usage data: We process data about your use of our website and services. The usage data
     may include your IP address, geographical location, browser type and version, operating
     system, referral source, length of visit, page views and website navigation paths, as well as
     information about the timing, frequency and pattern of your service use. The source of the
     usage data is our analytics tracking systems, Google Analytics and Matomo. Where this
     involves the use of cookies, we will ask you to consent to our use of any cookies that are not
     strictly necessary for the provision of our website and services. We process usage data for
     the purposes of analysing the use of the website and services and serving targeted
     invitations to participate in relevant market research activities to you. The legal basis for this
     processing is our legitimate interests, namely monitoring and improving our website and
     services and the performance of market research services on behalf of our clients.
2.3. Account data: We process personal data that you provide when registering to become a
     Doctors.net member and set up a Doctors.net account. Your account data comprises some
     personal data that is mandatory in order to join Doctors.net and set up an account and some
     personal data that is optional once you have become a member and set up an account.
     Once you have joined Doctors.net we will create an @doctors.net.uk email address for you,
     which will form part of your account data. We will also link the information you provide via

your account with your One Key ID (a unique identifier allocated to doctors), which we obtain
from Iqvia and will form part of your account data.
The data required in order to become a Doctors.net member (“mandatory account data”)
includes:
•     Whether you are a doctor or medical student
•     Your title
•     First name
•     Surname
•     GMC number
•     If you are a doctor:
      o     GMC number
      o     Specialty
      o     Sub-specialty
      o     Seniority
      o     Work postcode
      o     Graduation year
•     If you are a student:
      o     Medical school
      o     Expected year of graduation
      o     Image of your medical student card
We will use this data for the purpose of verifying that you are a GMC-registered doctor or
medical student, as membership of Doctors.net is only available to GMC-registered doctors
and medical students. We will also use the name you provide for the purpose of creating a
doctors.net.uk email address for you. The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate
interests, namely the proper administration of Doctors.net membership.
The data required in order to create an account (“account set up data”) includes:
•     Username
•     Password
•     Alternative email address
•     Mobile number

•     Place of birth
•     Mother’s maiden name
We will use this data for the purposes of creating an account for you, authenticating access to
your account, identifying you as the account holder, controlling and enabling you to access
areas of our website and services that are restricted to members and enabling you to reset
your password and gain access to your account if you forget your username or password.
The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate interests, namely ensuring the security of
our network, IT systems and information and providing Doctors.net members with a means of
accessing our website and services.
Use of your account data for market research purposes: If you have indicated that you
want to receive invitations to participate in market research, we will use your mandatory
account data for the purposes of:
•     inviting you to take part in market research activities relevant to your specialty and
      seniority
•     monitoring and enabling your participation in market research activities via our website,
      to ensure that you can only participate in the same activity once and that any incentives
      offered for taking part in such activities are correctly credited to you
This use of your data involves an element of profiling and automated decision making, in that
we screen our members (using automated means) on the basis of their specialty and
seniority so that only members falling within the specialty and seniority criteria specified by
our clients for specific market research activities are invited to participate in those activities.
This screening process is necessary in order to ensure that our clients are able to comply
with their legal obligations under the Association of the British Pharmaceutical Industry
(ABPI) code to target market research activities at medical professionals for whom the market
research is relevant/suitable according to their specialty and seniority.
We may invite you to participate in relevant market research activities by email to your
doctors.net.uk email address, by using messages delivered to your homepage when you
login to your doctors.net account, or (if you have so requested) by text or telephone call.
You can opt-out of receiving these email invitations at any time and indicate whether you
would like to receive invitations via text or telephone call by changing your communications
preferences at https://www.doctors.net.uk/updateyourprofile/default.aspx.
The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate interests, namely providing market
research services to our clients, and the legitimate interests of our clients in obtaining market
research data about their products or businesses in compliance with legal obligations to
which they are subject. Where incentives are offered in return for taking part, the legal basis
for our processing of your account data for the purposes of crediting you with those
incentives will be performance of a contract.

Use of your account data for marketing and communications purposes: We will use
your mandatory account data to send the following marketing and communications to your
@doctors.net.uk email address:
•    Clinical Bulletin: we will only send this to you if you have indicated that you want to
     receive them, as it contains promotional material on behalf of our clients. The content of
     the Clinical Bulletin is tailored to be relevant to your specialty and seniority and is
     targeted at you based on those criteria. Our delivery of the Clinical Bulletin to you
     therefore involves an element of profiling and automated decision making. This is
     necessary in order to ensure that our clients are able to comply with their legal
     obligations under the Association of the British Pharmaceutical Industry (ABPI) code to
     ensure that any promotional material sent to medical professionals is suitable and
     relevant according to their specialty and seniority.
•    Occasional promotional content from our clients: we will only send such emails to you
     if you have indicated that you want to receive them, as they contain promotional material
     on behalf of our clients. These emails are targeted at you based on your specialty and
     seniority. Our delivery of these emails to you therefore involves an element of profiling
     and automated decision making. This is necessary in order to ensure that our clients
     are able to comply with their legal obligations under the ABPI code to ensure that any
     promotional material sent to medical professionals is suitable and relevant according to
     their specialty and seniority.
•    Daily News Bulletin: we will send this to you unless you tell us that you don’t want to
     receive it. The Daily News Bulletin does not contain promotional material and enables
     you to keep up to date with the latest healthcare news. There is no tailoring of content
     or targeting involved in delivering the Daily News Bulletin to you.
•    Jobs Bulletin: we will send this to you unless you tell us that you don’t want to receive
     it. The Jobs Bulletin does not contain any promotional material and enables you to be
     informed of job opportunities that may of interest to you. The content of the Jobs
     Bulletin is tailored to be relevant to your specialty and seniority and is targeted at you
     based on those criteria. Our delivery of the Jobs Bulletin to you therefore involves an
     element of profiling and automated decision making.
•    Occasional client-specific recruitment-related emails: we will send you these unless
     you tell us that you don’t want to receive them. They do not contain any promotional
     material and enable you to be informed of job opportunities that may of interest to you.
     These emails will be targeted at you based on your specialty and seniority. Our delivery
     of the Jobs Bulletin to you therefore involves an element of profiling and automated
     decision making.
•    Specialty-specific updates (such as our Oncology and Rheumatology Updates): we
     will only send these to you if you have indicated that you want to receive them.
•    Member status updates: we will send emails relating to changes to your member
     status unless you tell us that you don’t want to receive them.

•     Postal mailing relating to Doctors.net service updates: we will send these to you if
      you tell us that you want to receive them.
•     SMS messages relating to your Doctors.net account: we will send these to you if
      you tell us that you want to receive them.
•     Job Alerts and Blog alerts: we will send these to you if you tell us that you want to
      receive them, in accordance with the frequency preference you specify.
•     Other communications that we may add from time to time and notify you of via your
      account, giving you the opportunity to opt-in or opt-out.
You can opt-in and opt-out to all of the above communications at any time by changing your
communications preferences at https://www.doctors.net.uk/updateyourprofile/default.aspx.
You can also opt-out from any specific communications by using the unsubscribe facility in
the communication itself. This will also automatically update your preferences. We may also
prompt you from time to time to revisit and update your communication preferences with the
aim of ensuring that we only send you relevant and wanted communications.
We will also use your account data to serve you with targeted advertising on behalf our
clients and other advertisers on our website. For further details please see Section 15.1 (c)
and 16.
The legal basis for this processing is legitimate interests, namely:
•     our interests in providing marketing, advertising, communications, market research and
      recruitment-related services to our clients, providing relevant information to our
      members and operating our business and website
•     our clients’ interests in promoting and advertising their products or recruiting suitable
      candidates for jobs with them.
Using your account data for our own marketing purposes: We will use your email
address and/or postal address in order to let you know about our range of products and
services for our own internal marketing purposes. This may, for example, include postal
mailings about our products and services if you have not visited our website recently. The
legal basis for this processing is our legitimate interests, namely to communicate our range of
products and services, and improvements to them, to our members.
Using your account data to create your profile: If you choose to have a visible profile in
our Member Directory, the following account data will by default be displayed in your profile:
•     name
•     specialty
•     seniority
•     year of graduation

     •     profile picture (if you have uploaded one)
     You can choose to display a visible profile, or remove your visible profile once published, at
     any time by using the settings made available via your Doctors.net account.
     You can also choose to provide any of the following optional information to appear in your
     profile:
     •     Clinical interests
     •     Employment status
     •     Medical school
     •     Defence body
     •     Your organisation address/es
     •     Additional professional roles
     •     Colleges and faculties
     •     Specialist societies
     •     Profile pictures
     •     Profile description
     •     Home address
     •     Any other optional fields
     You can add, remove or amend this information at any time by using the settings made
     available via your Doctors.net account.
     We will use the relevant account data for the purpose of making your profile available in our
     Member Directory. The legal basis for this processing is that it is our legitimate interests in
     providing a networking and communications platform for our members and making your
     profile available to other members at your request.
2.4. Data collected as a result of your participation in market research activities: If you take
     part in any market research activities, we will process some of your account data as
     necessary to enable you to participate in the research. Except in the limited circumstances
     explained below, we do not disclose your account data to the client for whom we are
     conducting the research.
     We will also process the information given by you in response to the survey questions
     (“market research data”).
     We may disclose certain personal data about you to the client for whom we are conducting
     the research in the following circumstances: if your responses include any information

     pertaining to the safety of, or an adverse event connected with, a pharmaceutical product (an
     “adverse event”), we are required by law and under our contract with the client to report such
     adverse event to the client. The client will then be required by law to take certain actions in
     respect of the adverse event. This may include contacting you to obtain further information
     about the adverse event. In these circumstances we would provide your name, title and
     contact details to the client to enable them to do this. The legal basis for this disclosure is
     that it is [necessary for compliance with a legal obligation].
2.5. Publication data: If you post any content for publication on our website or through our
     services when you are logged into Doctors.net, such as forum posts and the submission of
     clinical cases and images, we will process your username and any personal data contained
     in the content you post. The publication data will be processed for the purposes of enabling
     such publication and identifying you as the source of the content. The legal basis for this
     processing is our legitimate interests, namely the proper administration of our website and
     business, which is based upon a community website with member contributions.
2.6. Enquiry data: We will process information contained in any enquiry you submit to us
     regarding products and/or services advertised on our website, such as when you complete a
     form requesting more information, a callback or newsletter communications from a range of
     organisations who use our website to share promotional and/or educational content relating
     to their products and services. We will process your enquiry data for the purposes of
     responding to your enquiry, and if you request to be contacted directly by a relevant third
     party organisation, we will pass the contact details you used to make your enquiry to the
     relevant third-party organisation for this purpose. The legal basis for this processing is our
     legitimate interests in communicating with our members and our clients’ legitimate interests in
     contacting our members where requested by an individual member.
2.7. Transaction data: We may process information relating to transactions, including purchases
     of goods and services that you enter into with us and/or through our website, such as the
     conversion of eSR (electronic Surfing Reward) points to cash to buy merchandise or
     vouchers or donate to charity. The transaction data may include your email address, name
     and home address, and the transaction details. The transaction data may be processed for
     the purpose of supplying the purchased goods and services, the legal basis for this being the
     performance of a contract between you and us. We will also keep records of those
     transactions, the legal basis for this being our legitimate interests in the proper administration
     of our business.
2.8. Correspondence data: We will process information contained in or relating to any
     communication that you send to us. The correspondence data provided via email or
     telephone calls may be processed for the purposes of communicating with you, logging your
     communication through our Member Services system, and for the management of your
     account. The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate interests, namely the proper
     administration of our website and business and communications with users.
2.9. Using your personal data for other purposes: In addition to the specific purposes for
     which we may process your personal data set out in this Section 2, we may also process any
     of your personal data where such processing is necessary for:

     •     compliance with a legal obligation to which we are subject
     •     protecting your vital interests or the vital interests of another natural person
     •     obtaining or maintaining insurance coverage, managing risks, or obtaining professional
           advice. (The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate interests, namely the
           proper protection of our business against risks)
     •     the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims, whether in court proceedings or
           in an administrative or out-of-court procedure. (The legal basis for this processing is our
           legitimate interests, namely the protection and assertion of our legal rights, your legal
           rights and the legal rights of others.)
2.10.Other peoples’ personal data: Please do not supply any other person’s personal data to us,
     unless we prompt you to do so.
3.   Automated decision-making
3.1 We will use your relevant account data for the purposes of automated decision-making in
     relation to deciding what content you will see on the site, what content will be delivered to
     you, and which market research surveys will be offered to you. This will usually require an
     element of screening against your specialty and seniority for the purposes of delivering
     relevant and suitable content and invitations. This is described in more detail in section 2.
3.2 The significance and possible consequences of this automated decision-making are that it
     will affect what content you will see on our site or receive and what invitations to participate in
     market research you will receive.
3.3 We encourage you to keep your account data up to date, to ensure that the content and
     invitations delivered to you are relevant and suitable.
4.   Providing your personal data to others
4.1 We may disclose your personal data to any member of our group of companies (this means
     our subsidiaries, our ultimate holding company and all its subsidiaries) insofar as reasonably
     necessary for the purposes set out in this policy.
4.2 We may disclose your personal data to our insurers and/or professional advisers insofar as
     reasonably necessary for the purposes of obtaining and maintaining insurance coverage,
     managing risks, obtaining professional advice and managing legal disputes.
4.3 We may disclose your profile data to our suppliers or subcontractors insofar as reasonably
     necessary in order to deliver key parts of our website services, such as a jobs board. We
     may disclose your data to third-parties who supply services, such as Volcanic, who provide a
     jobs board, Mouseflow, who provide site recordings for website usage analysis, and Happy
     Fox, who provide a helpdesk portal.
4.4 Financial transactions relating to our website and services may be handled by our payment
     service providers, PayPal, Stripe and WorldPay. We will share transaction data with our
     payment service providers only to the extent necessary for the purposes of processing your

    payments, refunding such payments and dealing with complaints and queries relating to such
    payments and refunds. You can find information about the payment service providers’ privacy
    policies and practices for Paypal at https://www.paypal.com/en/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full
    for Stripe at https://stripe.com/gb/privacy and for WorldPay at
    https://www.worldpay.com/uk/privacy-policy.
4.5 We may disclose your enquiry data to one or more of those selected third-party organisations
    identified on our website, for the purposes of the third-party organisations offering relevant
    products and/or services to you.
    Categories of these third-party organisations are as follows:
    •      Pharmaceutical companies
    •      Other companies in the healthcare industry
    •      Medical device companies
    •      Financial services companies
    •      Medical indemnity organisations
    •      Medical jobs boards
    •      Charities
    Each such third party will act as a data controller in relation to the enquiry data that we supply
    to it; and such third party’s own privacy policy will govern that third party's use of your
    personal data.
4.6 In addition to the specific disclosures of personal data set out in this Section 4, we may also
    disclose your personal data where such disclosure is necessary for compliance with a legal
    obligation to which we are subject, or in order to protect your vital interests or the vital
    interests of another natural person.
5.  International transfers of your personal data
5.1 In this Section 5, we provide information about the circumstances in which your personal data
    may be transferred to countries outside the European Economic Area (EEA).
5.2 We and our other group companies have offices and facilities in China, India, Japan, South
    Korea, Latin America, and the United States. Transfers to each of these countries will be
    protected by appropriate safeguards, namely the use of standard data protection clauses
    adopted or approved by the European Commission. For further details please contact us.
5.3 The hosting facilities for our website are situated in the EEA.
5.4 Our Networks in Health partners situated in Australia, Austria, Belgium, Brazil, Canada,
    Finland, France, Germany, Hungary, Ireland, Italy, Latin America, Luxembourg, New
    Zealand, Portugal, Russia, Spain, Sweden, The Netherlands, Turkey. Transfers to each of
    these countries which are outside of the EEA will be protected by appropriate safeguards,

    namely the use of standard data protection clauses adopted or approved by the European
    Commission. For further details please contact us.
5.5 You acknowledge that personal data that you submit for publication through our website or
    services may be available, via the internet, around the world. We cannot prevent the use (or
    misuse) of such personal data by others.
6.  Retaining and deleting personal data
6.1 This Section 6 sets out our data retention policies and procedure, which are designed to help
    ensure that we comply with our legal obligations in relation to the retention and deletion of
    personal data.
6.2 Personal data that we process for any purpose or purposes shall not be kept for longer than
    is necessary for that purpose or those purposes.
6.3 We will retain and delete your personal data as follows:
     (a)    Your account data, transaction data and correspondence data will be retained for three
            years from the date on which your account has become inactive. (For the definition of
            ‘inactive’, see Terms and Conditions, section 2.7 for details) After this period, this data
            will be deleted from our systems, and we will instruct our other offices and Networks in
            Health partners to also delete this data if they hold it.
     (b)    Your usage data and market research data are anonymised, and will be retained.
     (c)      Your publication data and correspondence data will be retained, but only your
            username will be retained for reference, and all other personal details will be
            anonymised.
6.5  Notwithstanding the other provisions of this Section 6, we may retain your personal data
     where such retention is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which we are
     subject, or in order to protect your vital interests or the vital interests of another natural
     person.
7.   Security of personal data
7.1  We will take appropriate technical and organisational precautions to secure your personal
     data and to prevent the loss, misuse or alteration of your personal data.
7.2  We will store all your personal data on secure servers, personal computers and mobile
     devices, and in secure manual record-keeping systems.
7.3  All of your personal data will be stored by us in encrypted form.
7.4  Data relating to your enquiries and financial transactions that is sent from your web browser
     to our web server, or from our web server to your web browser, will be protected using
     encryption technology.
7.5  You acknowledge that the transmission of unencrypted (or inadequately encrypted) data
     over the internet is inherently insecure, and we cannot guarantee the security of data sent

    over the internet. GMC and BMA guidance states that doctors should not send any patient
    identifiable data across the internet. You should not post patient identifiable information on
    the website (including the forum). The email service that we provide as part of your
    membership is not encrypted, so it is especially important that you do not use it for the
    transfer of patient identifiable data. If you choose to use the Doctors.net.uk email service to
    transfer such data that you have yourself encrypted, then you do so at your own risk.
7.6 You should ensure that your password is not susceptible to being guessed, whether by a
    person or a computer program. You are responsible for keeping the password you use for
    accessing our website confidential and your password will only be used when you log in to
    our website. We will never ask you for your password.
8.  Amendments
8.1 We may update this policy from time to time by publishing a new version on our website.
8.3 We may notify you of changes to this policy by email or through the website.
9.  Your rights
9.1 In this Section 9, we have summarised the rights that you have under data protection law.
    Accordingly, you should read the relevant laws and guidance from the regulatory authorities
    for a full explanation of these rights.
9.2 Your principal rights under data protection law are:
    (a)    the right to access;
    (b)    the right to rectification;
    (c)    the right to erasure;
    (d)    the right to restrict processing;
    (e)    the right to object to processing;
    (f)    the right to data portability;
    (g)    the right to complain to a supervisory authority; and
    (h)    the right to withdraw consent.
9.3 You have the right to confirmation as to whether or not we process your personal data and,
    where we do, access to the personal data, together with certain additional information. That
    additional information includes details of the purposes of the processing, the categories of
    personal data concerned and the recipients of the personal data. Providing the rights and
    freedoms of others are not affected, we will supply to you a copy of your personal data, after
    you supplied appropriate evidence of your identity (this will require you to log in). The first
    copy will be provided free of charge, but additional copies may be subject to a reasonable
    fee. You can access your account data by visiting https://personal-data.doctors.net.uk/ when
    logged into the website.

9.4  You have the right to have any inaccurate personal data about you rectified and, taking into
     account the purposes of the processing, to have any incomplete personal data about you
     completed. You have the ability to update and complete your account data yourself on the
     Update Your Profile page on the website.
9.5  In some circumstances, you have the right to the erasure of your personal data without
     undue delay and which we will endeavor to do within 30 days of your request. Those
     circumstances include: the personal data are no longer necessary in relation to the purposes
     for which they were collected or otherwise processed; you withdraw consent to consent-
     based processing; the processing is for direct marketing purposes; and the personal data
     have been unlawfully processed. However, there are certain general exclusions of the right
     to erasure. Those general exclusions include where processing is necessary for exercising
     the right of freedom of expression and information and for compliance with a legal obligation;
     or for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims.
9.6  In some circumstances, you have the right to restrict the processing of your personal data.
     Those circumstances are: you contest the accuracy of the personal data; processing is
     unlawful but you oppose erasure; we no longer need the personal data for the purposes of
     our processing, but you require personal data for the establishment, exercise or defence of
     legal claims; and you have objected to processing, pending the verification of that objection.
     Where processing has been restricted on this basis, we may continue to store your personal
     data. However, we will only otherwise process it: with your consent; for the establishment,
     exercise or defence of legal claims; for the protection of the rights of another natural or legal
     person; or for reasons of important public interest.
9.7  You have the right to object to our processing of your personal data on grounds relating to
     your particular situation, but only to the extent that the legal basis for the processing is that
     the processing is necessary for: the performance of a task carried out in the public interest or
     in the exercise of any official authority vested in us; or the purposes of the legitimate
     interests pursued by us or by a third party. If you make such an objection, we will cease to
     process the personal information unless we can demonstrate compelling legitimate grounds
     for the processing which override your interests, rights and freedoms, or the processing is for
     the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims. If you object specifically to the
     processing of your account data, then fulfilment of this request will require the termination of
     your membership of Doctors.net.uk.
9.8  You have the right to object to our processing of your personal data for direct marketing
     purposes (including profiling for direct marketing purposes). If you make such an objection,
     we will cease to process your personal data for this purpose.
9.9  You have the right to object to our processing of your personal data for scientific or historical
     research purposes or statistical purposes on grounds relating to your particular situation,
     unless the processing is necessary for the performance of a task carried out for reasons of
     public interest.
9.10 To the extent that the legal basis for our processing of your personal data is consent, and
     such processing is carried out by automated means, you have the right to receive your

     personal data from us in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format.
     However, this right does not apply where it would adversely affect the rights and freedoms of
     others.
9.11 If you consider that our processing of your personal information infringes data protection
     laws, you have a legal right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority responsible for
     data protection. You may do so in the EU member state of your habitual residence, your
     place of work or the place of the alleged infringement.
9.12 To the extent that the legal basis for our processing of your personal information is consent,
     you have the right to withdraw that consent at any time. Withdrawal will not affect the
     lawfulness of processing before the withdrawal.
9.13 You may exercise any of your rights in relation to your personal data by contacting our
     Member Services team by telephone or email.
10.  Third party websites
10.1 Our website includes hyperlinks to, and details of, third party websites.
10.2 We have no control over, and are not responsible for, the privacy policies and practices of
     third parties.
11.  Personal data of children
11.1 Our website and services are targeted at persons over the age of 18.
11.2 If we have reason to believe that we hold personal data of a person under that age in our
     databases, we will delete that personal data.
12.  Updating information
12.1 Please let us know if the personal information that we hold about you needs to be corrected
     or updated. You can also update this on the Update your profile section of the website.
13.  Acting as a data processor
13.1 In respect of data provided from the GMC Register, HSCIC, and IMS Health, we do not act
     as a data controller; instead, we act as a data processor.
13.2 Insofar as we act as a data processor rather than a data controller, this policy shall not apply.
     Our legal obligations as a data processor are instead set out in the contract between us and
     the relevant data controller.
14.  About cookies
14.1 A cookie is a file containing an identifier (a string of letters and numbers) that is sent by a
     web server to a web browser and is stored by the browser. The identifier is then sent back to
     the server each time the browser requests a page from the server.

14.2 Cookies may be either "persistent" cookies or "session" cookies: a persistent cookie will be
     stored by a web browser and will remain valid until its set expiry date, unless deleted by the
     user before the expiry date; a session cookie, on the other hand, will expire at the end of the
     user session, when the web browser is closed.
14.3 Cookies do not typically contain any information that personally identifies a user, but
     personal information that we store about you may be linked to the information stored in and
     obtained from cookies.
15.  Cookies that we use
15.1 We use cookies for the following purposes:
     (a)   authentication - we use cookies to identify you when you visit our website, if you are
           logged in, as you navigate our website, and to protect our website and services
           generally. Cookies used for this purpose include:
         •  authcookies
         •  connect.marvin.session.sid
         •  connect.oauth-clinaccess-bridge.sid
         •  *.sid
         •  _user_logged_in
     (b)   personalisation - we use cookies to store information about your preferences and to
           personalise our website for you. Cookies used for this purpose include: us_lang
     (c)   advertising - we use cookies to help us to display advertisements that will be relevant
           to you. Cookies used for this purpose include:
         •  mc (.quantserve.com)
         •  ADMARK (.adtech.de)
         •  ck1 (.rlcdn.com)
         •  PUBMDCID (.pubmatic)
         •  bku (.bluekai.com)
     (d)   analysis - we use cookies to help us to analyse the use and performance of our
           website and services. Cookies used for this purpose include:
         •  _pk_id.36.80cd
         •  _privy_a
         •  mf_user
         •  _cfduid
     (e)   cookie consent - we use cookies to store your preferences in relation to the use of
           cookies more generally. Cookies used for this purpose include: doctors-net-uk-cookies.
16.  Cookies used by our service providers

16.1 Our service providers use cookies and those cookies may be stored on your computer when
     you visit our website.
16.2 We use Google Analytics and Matomo (formerly Piwik Analytics) to analyse the use of our
     website. Both reporting systems gather- information about website use by means of cookies.
     The information gathered relating to our website is used to create reports about the use of
     our website. Google's privacy policy is available at: https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/.
     Matomo’s privacy policy is available at: https://matomo.org/privacy/ The relevant cookies for
     Google Analytics are: _ga, _ga_privy _gid. The relevant cookies for Matomo are: _pk_*
16.3 We publish Google AdSense interest-based advertisements on our website. These are
     tailored by Google to reflect your interests. To determine your interests, Google will track
     your behaviour on our website and on other websites across the web using cookies. You can
     view, delete or add interest categories associated with your browser by visiting:
     https://adssettings.google.com. You can also opt out of the AdSense partner network cookie
     using those settings or using the Network Advertising Initiative's multi-cookie opt-out
     mechanism at: http://optout.networkadvertising.org. However, these opt-out mechanisms
     themselves use cookies, and if you clear the cookies from your browser your opt-out will not
     be maintained. To ensure that an opt-out is maintained in respect of a particular browser,
     you may wish to consider using the Google browser plug-ins available at:
     https://support.google.com/ads/answer/7395996.
16.4 We use Mouseflow to record visits and track usage patterns on specific web pages. You can
     view the privacy policy of this service provider at https://mouseflow.com/privacy/. The
     relevant cookies are: _privy_a, _privy_*, mf_user, optimizelyEndUserId, _ar_v4, _zlcmid,
     _mfsw_* and mf_lang
17.  Managing cookies
17.1 Most browsers allow you to refuse to accept cookies and to delete cookies. The methods for
     doing so vary from browser to browser, and from version to version. You can however obtain
     up-to-date information about blocking and deleting cookies via these links:
     (a)    https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95647?hl=en (Chrome);
     (b)    https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/enable-and-disable-cookies-website-preferences
            (Firefox);
     (c)    http://www.opera.com/help/tutorials/security/cookies/ (Opera);
     (d)    https://support.microsoft.com/en-gb/help/17442/windows-internet-explorer-delete-
            manage-cookies (Internet Explorer);
     (e)    https://support.apple.com/kb/PH21411 (Safari); and
     (f)    https://privacy.microsoft.com/en-us/windows-10-microsoft-edge-and-privacy (Edge).
17.2 Blocking all cookies will have a negative impact upon the usability of many websites.
17.3 If you block cookies, you will not be able to use all the features on our website.

18.  Our details
18.1 This website is owned and operated by M3 (EU) Ltd.
18.2 We are registered in England and Wales under registration number 3527430, and our
     registered office is at 20 Western Avenue, Milton Park, Abingdon, Oxfordshire, OX14 4SH.
18.3 Our principal place of business is at 20 Western Avenue, Milton Park, Abingdon,
     Oxfordshire, OX14 4SH.
18.4 You can contact us:
     (a)   by post, using the postal address given above;
     (b)   by telephone, on +44(0)1235 828400; or
     (d)   by email, using help@doctors.org.uk.
19.  Data protection registration
19.1 We are registered as a data controller with the UK Information Commissioner's Office.
19.2 Our data protection registration number is Z5861600.
20.  Data protection officer
20.1 Our data protection officer is Nesrine Boukri. Contact details are: DPO@eu.m3.com.
